(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T05:43:20.089137",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はぁ、みこちのライブもすぐだね。
Ah, Miko-chi's live is coming up so soon.
楽しみだな。
I'm so excited.
だね！
Right!
みこちも緊張してるだろうな。
Miko-chi must be so nervous.
だね。会場で待ってるみんなもドキドキしてるよね。
Exactly. Everyone waiting at the venue must be thrilled, too.
僕たち0期生も久しぶりに揃うね。
All of us 0th Gen are getting together after a long time, too.
0期生って、あんまり認知されてないよね。
0th Gen isn't really that well known, is it?
確かに。また一緒に何かしたいね。
True... I'd love for us to do something together again.
はっ！
Oh!
そろそろそらちゃん番だ。
It's almost Sora-chan's turn.
みこち、お帰り！2周年おめでとう！
Miko-chi, welcome back! Happy 2nd anniversary!
おめでとう、みこちゃん！
Congratulations, Miko-chan!
それでは、そらちゃんにバトンタッチ！
Now, passing the baton to Sora-chan!
みこちゃんをお待ちの皆さん、こんにちは！ときのそらです。
Hello everyone waiting for Miko-chan! I'm Tokino Sora.
本日はさくらみこ2周年＆復帰ライブにお越し下さり、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for attending Sakura Miko's 2nd Anniversary & Return Live today!
皆さん、もうすぐですよ！
Everyone, it's almost time!
ドキドキしてる？
Are you excited?
いや、私はすっごいドキドキしてます！
Man, I'm super nervous!
開催させていただいてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for letting us hold this.
皆さん、おかえりっていう準備はできていかな…
Everyone, are you ready to say "welcome back"...?
かわいいみこちゃんに、わぁって言う準備はできてますかー！
Are you ready to go "Wah!" for cute Miko-chan?!
心の準備もできてますかー！
Are you mentally prepared, too?!
元気にライブを楽しむ準備、大丈夫ですかねぇ？
Are you all set to energetically enjoy the live?!
それでは、そろそろライブが始まります！
Well then, the live is about to start soon!
皆さん、ペンライトの準備はできてますかー？
Everyone, do you have your penlights ready?
あ、そうそう。ハッシュタグは #さくらみこ復帰LIVE ですよ！
Ah, right. The hashtag is #SakuraMikoReturnLIVE!
たくさんスクショして呟いてくださいね！そしてコメントでたくさん応援してあげてください！
Take lots of screenshots and tweet them! And please show her lots of support in the comments!
みんなで「おかえり」を言いましょう！
Let's all say "Welcome back" together!
それでは、ときのそらがお送りしました！みこちゃん、頑張ってね！
This has been Tokino Sora! Miko-chan, do your best!
わんつーで参拝
One, two, bow and pray,
みこみこみこ！
Miko Miko Miko!
にゃはろー！
Nyahallo!
みんなー！
Everyone!
ただいまー！
I'm home!
ついに来たよ お待たせ！
Finally here, thanks for waiting!
待ちに待ったうへへへ♪
Long-awaited, uhehehe♪
電脳世界からやってきた
Coming from the cyber world,
ウザカワ系バーチャル巫女アイドル
An annoyingly cute virtual shrine maiden idol!
わたしはそうエリート！ (エリート？)
I am, that's right, elite! (Elite?)
なんていったってエリート！ (あっへん！)
No matter what, I'm elite! (Ahen!)
エリート巫女？ エリートアイドル？
Elite shrine maiden? Elite idol?
そんなの両方に決まってるのよ
Well, of course I'm both of those!
いじわるも泣き虫もカミサマも！？
Meanies, crybabies, and even gods!?
崇めたら巫女パワーで 幸せ分けてあげてもいいんだよ？
Worship my shrine maiden power, and maybe I'll share some happiness!
みこみこみこで
Miko Miko Miko,
ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Honyahonya unya unya!
さくらさくらさくらり さくらみこ
Sakura sakura sakurari, Sakura Miko!
みこみこみこで
Miko Miko Miko,
むにゃむにゃぐーぐーぐー…
Munyamunya gu gu gu...
明日から本気だす！
I'll get serious starting tomorrow!
みこみこみこで
Miko Miko Miko,
ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Honyahonya unya unya!
金時はほにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃたぶんっ！
Kintoki is honyanyanyanya probably!
幸せの太鼓
The drum of happiness,
ポンポコリンリンリン！ みんな笑顔になれ！
Pon pokorin rin rin! Everyone, wear a smile!
わんつーで参拝 みこみこみこ！
One, two, bow and pray, Miko Miko Miko!
みーんな！ 見えてるよ！
Everyone! I can see you!
コメントたくさんしててね！
Leave lots of comments!
ちょっとだけ休憩したい
I want to take just a little break,
マイペースだけど許してね！
I'm going at my own pace, so forgive me!
実はこれもしゅぎょうのうちです
Actually, this is part of my training too!
そんなわけはなくはない…あっバレたーっ！
No way that's... Ah, I've been caught!
わたしはそうエリート！ (エリート？)
I am, that's right, elite! (Elite?)
嘘じゃないよエリート！ (どーや？)
No lies, I'm elite! (How's that?)
エリート巫女！ エリートアイドル！
Elite shrine maiden! Elite idol!
今日もがんばがんば頑張っていきましょう！
Let's keep doing our best today too!
ココロもよう曇り日 雨の日も！？ 問題ない巫女パワーで
Gloomy weather, rainy days too!? No problem with my shrine maiden power,
それ晴れ晴れエンドレスワイガヤしようよ！
Let's make it a bright, endless, lively parade!
みこみこみこで
Miko Miko Miko,
ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Honyahonya unya unya!
さくらさくらさくらり さくらみこ
Sakura sakura sakurari, Sakura Miko!
みこみこみこで
Miko Miko Miko,
むしゃむしゃぐーぐー…
Mushamusha gu gu...
たいやき食べてたいやき！
Eating taiyaki, taiyaki!
みこみこみこで
Miko Miko Miko,
ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Honyahonya unya unya!
カミサマもほにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃたぶんっ！
Even the gods, honyanyanyanya probably!
元気の呪文 みこみこまいまいまい！ みんな笑顔になれ！
The spell for energy, Miko Miko maimaimai! Everyone, wear a smile!
わんつーで参拝 みこみこみこ！
One, two, bow and pray, Miko Miko Miko!
にゃはろー！ みんなお久しぶり！
Nyahallo! Long time no see, everyone!
今日は２周年と復帰ライブ！
Today is my 2nd anniversary and return live!
全体に盛り上げてくぜー！
Let's get everyone super hyped up!
お手を拝借！ はい、みっ・ぽっ・みっ・こっ！
Lend me your hands! Ready, mi-po-mi-ko!
みこ！みこ！みこはエリート！
Miko! Miko! Miko is elite!
エリート！エリート！イエーイ！！
Elite! Elite! Yeah!!
ラストにもう一回はりきっていくよー！
Let's go all out one last time!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Miko Miko Miko, honyahonya unya unya!
さくらさくらさくらり さくらみこ
Sakura sakura sakurari, Sakura Miko!
みこみこみこで むにゃむにゃぐーぐー…
Miko Miko Miko, munyamunya gu gu...
ミョーガはひょちょひょちょ？
Myoga is hyochohyocho?
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Miko Miko Miko, honyahonya unya unya!
金時はほにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃたぶんっ！
Kintoki is honyanyanyanya probably!
幸せの太鼓 ポンポコリンリンリン！
The drum of happiness, pon pokorin rin rin!
みんな笑顔になれ！ わんつーで参拝 みこみこみこ！
Everyone, wear a smile! One, two, bow and pray, Miko Miko Miko!
この曲、聴いてくれて
Thank you for listening to this song,
本当にありがとう…！
Thank you so much...!
わんつーで参拝 みこみこみこ！
One, two, bow and pray, Miko Miko Miko!
最後も参拝 みこみこみこ！イエーイ！
Final prayer, Miko Miko Miko! Yeah!
おしまい！
That's the end!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
はぁ ということで
Phew... So,
皆さん
everyone,
お久しぶりの方は…どうも、お久しぶりです。
for those it's been a while... hello, it's been a while.
だめだめ、最初はね、だめだよ。
No, no, at first, no, I can't do it.
ちょっと待って。
Hold on...
はい、皆さん！
Hi, everyone!
初めましての人は…初めまして！
For those meeting me for the first time... nice to meet you!
さくらみこです！えにこみこの…さくらみこです！
I'm Sakura Miko! Eniko Miko's... Sakura Miko!
本当に、本当にたくさん待ってくれて、どうもありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for waiting for me for so, so long.
えみこは、3ヶ月半…ぐらいかな？
Emiko was... about 3 and a half months, I guess?
ちょっとだけ…ちょっとじゃない、長い間ね、
For a little while... no, not a little, for a long time,
配信もお休みして…急ように開けてくれて、みんなをほっといて…本当にごめんなさい！
I took a break from streaming... opening up so suddenly and leaving everyone hanging... I am truly sorry!
そして…ありがとうございます！
And... thank you so much!
今日もね、支えてくれたこのライブのメンバーも、
Today as well, supporting me, the members of this live,
みこぴーも、今見てくれてるこのライブのファンの方も、初めてしてくれた方も、
Mikopii as well, the fans watching this live right now, those meeting me for the first time,
スタッフさんも、お母さんも…
the staff, my mom...
今日までたくさん迷惑をかけて、心配かけて…それでも、この先まで元気に活動できるようにと、給料を取らせて…もらっていました。
up until today, causing so much trouble and worry... even so, wishing that I can continue my activities energetically moving forward, I was allowed to take a salary... receive it.
そして今日！待望の、待ちに待った復帰ライブ！
And today! The long-awaited, eagerly awaited return live!
めっちゃ緊張してるけど、ダンスも下手だったかな？まあ、リトだけど…今日も頑張ったんだけど。そう。
I'm super nervous, but was my dance bad too? Well, it's lito... but I did my best today. Yeah.
今日は精一杯、復帰を楽しんでいきたいと思います！コメント見れないよー。
Today I want to enjoy my return to the fullest! I can't see the comments.
はあ、ありがとうみんな！
Phew, thank you everyone!
ホロライブ！ホロライブのメイジ、エリートみこ、センキュー！ああ、アーユルヴェーダ！ウォー！
Hololive! Hololive's mage, elite Miko, thank you! Ah, Ayurveda! Whoa!
ああ、楽しいね！久しぶりに会うと…なんか緊張する。
Ah, it's fun! Seeing you after such a long time... I feel kind of nervous.
でも、本当にありがとう。あ、みこ声変わってない？大丈夫？
But, thank you so much. Ah, has Miko's voice changed? Is it okay?
どうと…なんか、大丈夫？大丈夫かな。
Huh... somehow, is it okay? Is it okay, I wonder.
ということで、それではね、この後…どんどん…どんどん…お、おいかかわんないけど、何曲か歌わせてもらえます。
So, well then, after this... more and more... more and more... oh, I don't know why, but I'll get to sing a few songs.
頑張る！頑張るから、みんなよかったら最後まで見てください。
I'll do my best! I'll do my best, so everyone, if you'd like, please watch until the end.
そして、え、最後のほうには…お知らせも…ある！あるんだよ。なので、楽しみに…しててください。
And, um, towards the end... there's also... an announcement! There is. So please look forward to it.
ああ、ニコユーズで、はい！
Ah, Nico users, yes!
ということで、それでは次の曲、行っていいですか？
So with that, shall we go to the next song?
おいおい、楽しみだよ！
Oh boy, I'm looking forward to it!
はい、楽しみにしてくれてるということで！
Yes, since you're looking forward to it!
それでは、復帰ライブ始めたいと思います！
Well then, I'd like to start the return live!
まず1曲目は…マスターピース！
First, the first song is... MASTERPIECE!
M@STERPIECE 作詞：yura 作曲：神前暁
M@STERPIECE | Lyrics: yura | Music: Satoru Kosaki
さあ今を輝け!!
Now, shine in the present!!
YES→幾つもの思い出達
YES→Countless memories
眩しい今日の光へ
Toward today's dazzling light
さあ今を羽ばたけ!!
Now, take flight into the present!!
夢をはじめて寝かせて 今日までどのくらい経っただろう
I first let my dream sleep—wondering how much time has passed until today.
ずっと一日ずつ 繋げようよ
Let's keep connecting it, one day at a time.
歌いたいから
Because I want to sing,
踊りたいから
because I want to dance,
新しい幕を開けようね Maeveへ
let's open a new curtain toward the future—
愛のDiamond
with a diamond of love,
Masterpiece
our masterpiece.
夢をはじめて寝かせて 今日までどのくらい経っただろう
I first let my dream sleep—wondering how much time has passed until today.
ずっと一日ずつ 繋げようよ
Let's keep connecting it, one day at a time.
夢は自分を叶える
Dreams make ourselves come true,
たまに生まれた証だから
as proof that we were born this way.
きっと この心で 私のMasterpiece
Surely, right here in this heart, is my masterpiece.
ねぇ 逢えてよかった
Hey, I'm so glad we met.
ねぇ あなたに言葉言うなら
Hey, if I were to put it into words for you,
ありのままと そして よろしくスマイル
just be as you are, and keep a smiling face.
みんなでいても たった一人でいても
Whether we're together or completely alone,
輝きの向こう側へ 進め All right!
let's push forward beyond the radiance—all right!
明日はどんな日になるか 誰だって分からないけれど
Nobody knows what kind of day tomorrow will bring,
それはどんな秘密の出来事
whatever secret events await us.
明日は追いかけて雲のじゃなくて 今へと変えてくもの
Tomorrow isn't just something to chase, but something we turn into the present.
それが自分になる 私がマスターピース
That becomes who I am—my own masterpiece.
みんなのおかげで 戻って来てくれました！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to come back!
それは支えてくれた コロネースのみんな、３期生ののみんな、そして今見てくれてるみんなのおかげです！
That's thanks to everyone who supported me, my 3rd-gen peers, and all of you watching right now!
今日のライブ 楽しんでってねー！
Please enjoy today's live concert!
歌いたいから
Because I want to sing,
踊りたいから
because I want to dance,
新しい幕を開けようね Maeveへ
let's open a new curtain toward the future—
愛のDiamond
with a diamond of love,
Masterpiece
our masterpiece.
夢をはじめて寝かせて 今日までどのくらい経っただろう
I first let my dream sleep—wondering how much time has passed until today.
ずっと一日ずつ 繋げようよ
Let's keep connecting it, one day at a time.
夢は自分を叶える
Dreams make ourselves come true,
たまに生まれた証だから
as proof that we were born this way.
きっと この心で 私のMasterpiece
Surely, right here in this heart, is my masterpiece.
みこみさde...
Miko & Misa de...
はい！ということで、
Hi! So,
聞きてもらったのはみこがめっちゃくちゃ大好きマスターピースって曲です。みんな知ってますか？
the song you just heard is one of my absolute
favorites, 'Masterpiece'. Does everyone know it?
いますよね。あの劇場版のね、テーマのあの曲。
I'm sure you do. That theme song
from the theatrical version.
すっごくいい曲で。このライブのね、みんなとか、みこぴーとか、今見てくれてるみんなのこと考えて選曲しました。
It's such a wonderful song. I chose it
while thinking of everyone watching right now.
はい、ということで、え、ここからは皆さん気にされてたと思う、概要欄。
Hi, so, next up is something I think
you've all been curious about: the description.
オーロ・クロニーのほるじゅるとかさ、しゅけ、しゅけまるごてててててって。
Ouro Kronii's 'Horu-jul' or whatever... and
all those weird 'shuke-shukemaru' parts.
ということで、今日はですね、ホロライブメンバーに協力してもらったというか、いただいたものが
So today, we actually received some
contributions from the Hololive members,
あります。それを、今からみんなと一緒に見ていきたいなって思うんですけど、いいですか？
or rather, things they made for us.
I'd love to watch them with everyone, okay?
いや、本当に嬉しい。そう、大自身の、みこの、大好きなホロライブメンバーにいただきました。ありがとうございます、みんなに。そう、いただいたの。
Man, I'm so happy. Yes, I received them
from my absolute favorite Hololive members.
はい、ということで、それでは、VTR、スタート！
Hi, so, without further ado...
VTR, start!
みこみこー！
Miko-miko!
お帰りなさいのなのー！やったー！
Welcome back, nano! Yay!
やっと復帰できるとのこと、とっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy you can finally make your return!
あまり一緒遊んだり、映画に行ったりするよね。え、これからもどうぞよろしくなのだね！
We don't usually hang out or go to movies.
Please continue to treat me well, nano!
お鍋したりも！すきだよ！可愛い！みこより可愛い！みこー！
And eating hot pot together! I love you!
So cute! Cuter than Miko! Miko!
みこちゃん！あきちゃん！お帰り！
Miko-chan! Aki-chan! Welcome back!
お帰りっていうことができて本当に良かった！
I'm so glad I was able to say 'welcome back'!
あのね、みこちゃん。あきろで、新PCをやっと買って、できなくなってたマイクラがやっとできるように、なったよ！
You know, Miko-chan, I finally got a new PC,
so I can finally play Minecraft again!
おめでとー！新PCになってからの特訓も楽しかったし、またあきみこてぇてぇもしたいし、
Congratulations! Training on the new PC was
fun, and I want to do more AkiMiko moments,
あきろぜ的にはもっと仲良くしてくれたら嬉しいんだけどな。
and as AkiRosé, I'd be happy if we got
even closer.
いいよ！いいよ！ありがとう！これからも楽しいこと作っていこうね。本当にお帰り！
Okay! Okay! Thank you! Let's keep making
fun things together. Truly, welcome back!
はちゃまっちゃまー！はちゃまちゃだよー！
Hachamatchama! It's Hachamacha!
みこち、2周年＆復帰3Dライブおめでとう！ありがとう！
Miko-chi, congrats on your 2nd anniversary
and return 3D live! Thank you!
この超絶なすてきキュートなみこちがライブ会場にいることでしょう。
This super amazingly cute Miko-chi
must be at the live venue.
これからも、なに事にも真剣に取り組むみこちを、陰ながら応援してます！
I'll keep supporting Miko-chi from the shadows
as she earnestly tackles everything!
みこちも、みこみこ、みこみこって、みこちパワー全開で、これからも頑張ってね！みこみこお帰りなさい！
Miko-chi, do your best with full Miko-chi power!
Miko-miko, welcome back!
ありがとう！お、お、ん？
Thank you! Oh, oh, hmm?
な、な、なんと、F氏、みこちゃんが帰ってきただって！
W-W-What? Mr. F, Miko-chan is back?!
うおー！こうしちゃいられない！借金を推せても、ま、私もちゃんぶるーに身を染めなければ！
Whoa! I can't just sit here! Even if I'm
in debt, I must immerse myself in Gamblu!
し、師匠！カジノで、待っとるでー！みこで、カジノいくでー！頼むわ、ふーちゃん、あ！
M-Master! I'll be waiting at the casino!
Let's go to the casino! Please, Fu-chan, ah!
みこち、2周年＆復帰3Dライブおめでとう！ありがとう！
Miko-chi, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary
and return 3D live! Thank you!
みこちは本当に、ホロライブになくてはならない存在なんだなっていうのを、このお休みしている間にすごく感じました。
I really felt how indispensable Miko-chi is
to Hololive while you were taking a break.
なんか、企画とかもね、すごく楽しいの考えてくれるし、いつも感謝しております。
You always come up with such fun projects,
and I'm always grateful.
これからも元気で明るいみこちを、あの、見せてください。大好きだよ！夏色まつりでした！お帰り！
Please keep showing us your energetic and
bright self! I love you! Welcome back!
ありがとう！じゃあ今度こそ正真正銘だね。
Thank you! So this time it's for real, right?
二人合わせて、みっころねやーってやんよー！！
Together, Mikkorone Yatteyan yo!!
やったー！動画がしゅくしゅくなるね！これからも！動画がしゅくしゅくなるね。このメッセージでバグってるの、これ。重なってる、すごいことになってるよ。
Yay! The video is getting shuku-shuku!
This message is bugged. It's overlapping!
みこちゃーん！復帰＆2周年おめでとう！ちょうだい！
Miko-chan! Congratulations on your return
& 2nd anniversary! Give me!
みこちゃんが帰ってくるのをみんなずっと待ってたと思います。今日もずっと待ってました。
I think everyone has been waiting for Miko-chan
to come back. Today, everyone waited all day too.
これからもね、ホロライブメンバーとしてみこちゃんと楽しいね、企画とか色々一緒にできたらなって思います。そして2周年！
I hope we can do lots of fun projects together
as Hololive members. And happy 2nd anniversary!
本当におめでたいことが二つもおめでとう、みこちゃん！
Congratulations on two great achievements!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みこっち！
Miko-chi!
みこっち、みこっち、みこっち、はいはい！
Miko-chi, Miko-chi, Miko-chi, yay, yay!
これからもよろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you from now on!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、ハロー！
Yay, hello!
チョコ先生です！
Choco-sensei is here!
さくらみこちゃんだよー！
Sakura Miko-chan,
待って、ちゃんとサービス精神にありがとうございます。
Wait, Choco-sensei, are you taking this seriously? Thank you!
送るね。
I'm sending it.
いや、ハロー！
Yay, hello!
かわいいよ、かわいいよチョコ先生、送らないでね？
So cute, so cute, Choco-sensei, don't send it, okay?
はい。
Okay.
みこさま、2周年おめでとうございます！
Miko-sama, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして、お帰りなさい。また一緒に配信しようね。
And then... welcome back. Let's stream together again sometime, right?
あれだね、帰ってきた旦那さんに対してもメッセージを…
That's right, I sent a message to my husband who just came home!
みこっち！おめでとう、おめでとう、おめでとう、おめでとう！
Miko-chi! Congratulations, congratulations, congratulations, congratulations!
ということで、スバルもスバルのママもよーく喜んでおります！わーい！わーい！わーい！わーい！
So Subaru and Subaru's mom are overjoyed! Yay, yay, yay, yay!
みこっちが復帰したから、これからマインクラフトとか、企画とか、企画とか、企画とか、ゲームとか、ゲームとか、ゲームとか、いっぱい遊びたい！
Miko-chi is back, so from now on, Minecraft, planning, planning, planning, games, games, games, games, let's play a lot!
本当に復帰おめでとう！3Dライブ頑張ってね！
Really, really, welcome back! Congratulations on your 3D live! Do your best!
また遊ぼう！待っててね！
See you again, wait for me!
おかえりね！
Welcome back!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
夢見る空へ
To the Sky of Dreams
作詞・作曲・編曲：永塚健登
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Eitsuka Kento
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
With our intertwined hands held tightly without letting go,
行くよ！（行こう！）夢見る空へ
Let's go! (Let's go!) To the sky of dreams!
窓越しに見上げた とても小さな空
The tiny sky we looked up at through the window,
ここで出会えたのは 数え切れないキセキ
The countless miracles we met right here,
繰り返した一歩が キラメキをつないで
Each repeated step connecting the sparkles,
星のような笑顔 導いた
Led us to smiles like the stars.
day by day みんなの声が チカラになる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes our strength.
stage by stage ここで それぞれ目指すもの
Stage by stage, aiming for our respective goals,
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ願った夢へ
Drawing what each of us imagines, toward the dream we wished for.
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
With our intertwined hands held tightly without letting go,
ひとり（ひとり）違う（色で）描き出すトキメキ
With our own (unique) colors, we paint the sparkles,
振り返ることなく まっすぐ に
Going straight ahead without looking back,
行くよ！（行こう！）夢見る空へ
Let's go! (Let's go!) To the sky of dreams!
笑い合ったことや 尽きそうにない話題
Moments of sharing laughter and endless topics,
思い出いっぱい なのに あっという間の日々
So many memories, yet gone in the blink of an eye.
上書きではなくて 名前つけて保存
Instead of just rewriting, we name and save them,
どれも全部 大事って言い切れる
We can say every single one of them is precious.
one for all みんなのため が チカラになる
One for all, for everyone, becomes our strength.
all for all 今日も 賑やかすぎるくらい
All for all, today too, it's just too lively!
笑顔もう とまらない 想いは膨らんでいく
Smiles won't stop, our feelings keep growing.
重ねた今 ギュッと 噛み締め た
Holding our current selves tightly, biting down on the feeling,
ひとり（ひとり）違う（声で）歌声は広がる
With our own (unique) voices, our singing spreads out,
風を感じたら まっすぐ に
Feeling the wind, going straight ahead,
行くよ！（行こう！）夢見る空へ
Let's go! (Let's go!) To the sky of dreams!
憧れへ 手を 伸ばし 掴み取った その光 が
Reaching out our hands toward our longing, and catching that light—
いつの日 か また 誰かの憧れに変わる 繋げよう
Will one day turn into someone else's longing. Let's connect them!
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
With our intertwined hands held tightly without letting go,
ひとり（ひとり）違う（色で）描き出すトキメキ
With our own (unique) colors, we paint the sparkles,
出会えた 全てに ありがとう
Thank you for everything we encountered.
キセキ（だって）起こし（続け）
Miracles (they say) will happen (and continue),
ずっと（ずっと）そばにいるよ
Always (always) staying by your side.
行くよ！（行こう！）夢見る空へ
Let's go! (Let's go!) To the sky of dreams!
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our intertwined hands tightly,
ひとりひとり違う景色を描き出すときめき
The excitement of drawing different individual views,
出逢えたすべてにありがとうを
Saying thank you to everything we've encountered,
奇跡起こし続けるずっとそばにいるよ行くよ
Continuing to create miracles, always by your side, let's go,
夢見る空へ
Toward the sky of our dreams!
はい、ということで、えーなんとホロライブメンバーからね、
Yes, and with that... Um, sort of, from the Hololive members,
1期生と2期生の皆にいただきました。
the 1st and 2nd generation gave me messages.
本当にありがとう。
Thank you truly so much.
そして歌わせてもらったのは夢見る空へホロライブのね、楽曲です。
And the song I sang was Hololive's song, "Yumemiru Sora e".
これはね、コーラスに1期生のみんながね、入ってくれてます。ありがとう、みんなで一緒に歌った。
In this, the 1st gen members joined in for the chorus. Thank you, we sang together!
このさ、振り付けちょっと、ちょっとうまくいったでしょ？ここ。
And this choreography, I did it pretty well, right? Right here.
はい、というわけでそれでは早速次の曲という…
Yes, and with that, let's move right on to the next song—
次はもちろん…
Next is of course...
どうぞ！
Here it goes!
みこち！
Mikochi!
2周年おめでとう！
Happy 2nd anniversary!
うちがお休みしてたときにたくさん励ましてくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for encouraging me a lot when I was on break.
優しくてかわいいみこちの放送がまた見れるのかと思うと、すっごく嬉しいよ。
Knowing I can watch sweet and cute Mikochi's broadcasts again makes me so, so happy.
うちはみこちの放送、結構見てるからね。
After all, I watch Mikochi's broadcasts quite a lot.
これからも一緒に楽しく放送してこう！コラボとかもできたらいいな。
Let's keep broadcasting and having fun together! I hope we can do collabs too.
これからもよろしくね。
Please continue to take care of me.
ありがとうみこちゃん、本当に。
Thank you, Miko-chan, truly.
あ！
Ah!
おかえり！
Welcome back!
おかえりなさい！ただいま！帰ってくるのをずっと楽しみにしてました。
Welcome back! I'm back! I've been looking forward to you coming back.
みこちゃんがいない間に、僕はみこちゃんのモノマネを全然してなかったので、どんどんニャハローレベルが下がってきてます。
While Miko-chan was gone, I wasn't doing Miko-chan's impersonations at all, so my Nyahallo level has been dropping steadily.
それでは聞いてください。「下がりまに下がったみこちゃんのモノマネです」。
So please listen to: "The plummeting Nyahallo impersonation of Miko-chan".
ニャ、ハロー、あ、なんちゃって。
Nya, hallo... Ah, just kidding.
みこち！
Mikochi!
活動2周年おめでとう！
Happy 2nd anniversary of activities!
みこちゃんが戻ってくるときにやりたいことが溜まっていくからどうしてくれるんだか楽しみなんだけれども、
Since there's so many things you wanted to do piling up now that you're back, I'm looking forward to how you'll handle it,
これからはいっぱい、いっぱい楽しいことやっていこうね！
Let's do lots and lots of fun things from now on!
やりたいことは半分こすればいいからね。みこことも大好きだよ。
We can just split what we want to do. I love Mikochi too.
あ、こういうの大好きだよね、みこちゃん。ゆらおいのがみころね。
Ah, Miko-chan, you love this kind of stuff. Yuri is good, MikoKorone.
はい！
Yes!
みこせ…
Mikose...
おかえりなさい、ペコ！
Welcome back, Peko!
そして活動2周年おめでとう！
And happy 2nd anniversary of activities!
ありがとう、みこちゃん。
Thank you, Miko-chan.
元気になって戻ってきてくれてね、とっっても、とっってもペコらはね、嬉しいペコだよ。
We're so, so happy, Peko, that you came back full of energy.
その、そうだね、本当にねペコマリ、みこぜんそでできるペコだよね、ペコぺこー！
And well, really, PekoMari, MikoZenso, we can do it, Peko, right? Peko-peko!
遊ぶのを楽しみにしてるペコだから、ライブも頑張ってペコだよ！
We're looking forward to playing, Peko, so do your best in the live too, Peko!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
2周年おめでとう！
Happy 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうな。
Thank you.
こんにちは、みこ先輩。
Hello, Miko-senpai.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
うれしいです。
I'm so happy.
このたびは復帰おめでとうございます。
Congratulations on your return.
またこれからみこ先輩の配信でみんなをたくさんたくさん笑顔にしちゃってください。
Please continue to make everyone smile so, so much on Miko-senpai's streams.
みこ先輩の配信、楽しみにしてます。
I'm looking forward to Miko-senpai's streams.
そして本当に本当に改めて、みこ先輩おかえりなさい！
And truly, truly once again, welcome back, Miko-senpai!
そして配信復帰おめでとうございます！楽しみにしております。
And congratulations on your return to streaming! We're looking forward to it.
それでは失礼いたします。
Well then, excuse me.
かわいすぎないか、今の。
Wasn't that just too cute?
ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす。
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd generation.
みこ先輩！2周年おめでとうございます！
Miko-senpai! Congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そしてそして、おかえりなさい！待ってたよー！
And, and, welcome back! We've been waiting for you!
配信でもまたたくさん一緒に遊んでね。
Let's play together a lot more on stream too.
なさいね。
Please do.
いや、感動！
Man, I'm so moved!
前回もどこかで一緒に出たいですね。
I'd love to appear together somewhere again like last time.
出たい！
I want to!
最後まで楽しんで見てますからね。
I'll be enjoying and watching it until the very end.
みこ先パイも楽しんで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Miko-senpai, let's enjoy it and get hyped too!
がんばる！おめでとー！
Do your best! Congrats!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
白銀先パイ、2周年&配信復活おめでとうございます！
Shirogane-senpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary and streaming comeback!
しちゅ呼び！白銀先パイの楽しい配信がまた見れるときって、だんちょーすっごくすっごく嬉しいです。
Calling each other Shichu! When I get to watch Shirogane-senpai's fun streams again, Danchou is super, super happy.
体調に気をつけてね、いっぱい配信してくださいね！
Take care of your health, stream a lot!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして、だんちょーと次会ったら今度は一緒に牛丼食べに行きましょう！
And next time I meet Danchou, let's go eat gyudon together!
では改めてまして、本当に本当に、おめでとうございます！
So once again, truly, truly congratulations!
ありがとう！まじ新衣装楽しみ！
Thank you! I'm so looking forward to the new outfit!
みこ先パイ！みこち、とーっても嬉しいです！
Miko-senpai! Mikochi, I'm sooo happy!
みこ先パイがいない時に限ってね、みこ先パイでやりたいことをいっぱい思いついちゃったので、もう、ここからね、いっぱい、いろんなことを一緒にしていきましょう！
And just when Miko-senpai wasn't around, I thought of so many things I wanted to do with Miko-senpai, so from now on, let's do lots of things together!
そしてね、みこ先パイと3D配信をした時に、抱きしめたあのミコ先輩の感触がもう忘れられなくて...
And when I did a 3D stream with Miko-senpai, the feeling of hugging Miko-senpai, I just can't forget it...
みこ先パイ、次会った時は、次のステップへいきませんか？共に、みこ先パイ、一緒にしゅっこーしましょう！
Miko-senpai, when we meet next time, shall we go to the next step? Together, Miko-senpai, let's set sail together!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
でもあく、あくね、こういうこと言ってくれてありがとう！
But Aku, Aku-ne, thank you for saying stuff like this!
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so very much.
ようこそジャパリパークへ
[Title: Welcome to Japari Park]
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
うー! がー!
Grrr roar!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ
Laugh together and be friends, friends
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even if we fight and become uncontrollable, we are best friends
けものは居ても のけものはいない
There are animals, but there are no pariahs
本当の愛はここにある
The true love was here
ほら 君も手を繋いで大冒険
Here, let's go to adventure with you, too
(ワン・ツー・スリー)
(One, two, three)
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
There are different appearances and shapes for everyone, so we get attracted to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら はじめて
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun, nice to meet you
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you
うー! がー!
Grrr roar!
振り返ればあちらこちらでトラブル なんてことだ でんでんぱらぱらちんぷんかんぷんまとまらない
Look back and everywhere I see, there are troubles, troubles...
けものはもの 大目に見ててね みんな自由に生きている
We are animals, so forgive us. Everyone is living freely
そう 君も飾らなくても大丈夫
Yes, you don't have to maintain your image
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク!
Nice to meet you, in the Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
I'm so glad to meet you
いつでもいつまでも優しい笑顔 君を待っていたの
Smiling tenderly anytime, anywhere, we were waiting for you
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら 続いてくグレイテスト・ジャーニー
Gate that is open, after talking a lot about our dreams, great journey
Oh 東へ吠えろ 西へ吠えろ 世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Roar to east, roar to west, sound the safari melody all over the world
ここは2周年とホロライブ!
This is the 2nd anniversary and Hololive!
愛のに参加してくれたのは
Who participated in love was
ピカピカピカピカ!
Pika pika pika pika!
あ、はい! ほうしょうマリンです!
Ah, yes! Houshou Marine is here!
出航! 出発!
Set sail! Departure!
そして 新鮮な指はいかがですか? おー!
And how about some fresh fingers? Oh!
東へ吠えろ 西へ吠えろ 世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Roar to east, roar to west, sound the safari melody all over the world
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク!
Welcome to youkoso japari paaku!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
There are different appearances and shapes for everyone, so we get attracted to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら はじめて君をもっと知りたいな
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun, I want to know more about you
うー! がー!
Grrr roar!
ラララララ ラララララ Oh Welcome to the ジャパリパーク!
La la la la la la la la oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ラララララ ラララララ 集まれ友達
La la la la la la la la la la gather around, friends!
ラララララ ラララララ Oh Welcome to the ジャパリパーク!
La la la la la la la la oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日も ドッタンバッタン 大騒ぎ
Today is another loud ruckus!
うー！ がおー！
Roar! Growl!
高らかに 笑い 笑えば フレンズ
The louder we laugh, the better friends we become!
騒いで すっちゃかめっちゃかでも 仲良し
No matter how much we fight, we're still friends!
はーい、ちょっとまってね
Hii, wait a second...
イヤホン取れちゃった、いま…
My earphone came off, right now...
あー… ありがとう！
Ah... Thank you!
ありがとうね、みんな、ふふ…
Thank you everyone, hehe...
ちょっと、いま…
Hold on, right now...
あの遠くのストリーマーが耳に… イヤホンぶっこんじゃったから
That streamer in the distance... jammed the earphone right into my ear, so
よしこ… よしこ、あ、歌えなかった！
Yoshiko... Yoshiko, ah, I couldn't sing!
はーい！
Hii!
ということで、じゃんじゃん！
And with that, tada!
みてみてみてみてみて
Look, look, look, look, look!
みこお、さくらねこお、そして…
Miko, Sakura Neko, and...
こっちは… すぱちゃんね、あの、あんきも… あんきもの、だい！
And over here is Supe-chan's... um, Ankimo's giant!
そしてこっちは… ぬのひめのね、羊の牛の、だい！
And Nuno-hime's sheep and cow giant!
おっ、あ、なん、なん…
Oh, ah, wha, wha...
びず、えむ、やーい！
BIZM, yay!
かわいいでしょこれ、ぷにぷにぷにぷに…
Isn't this cute? Squishy, squishy...
ほらほら、ぷにぷにぷにぷに…
Look, look, squishy, squishy...
そう、これね、あの、来てもらいまして、ありがとうございました！
Yeah, thanks for coming here, thank you so much!
あ、みてかって、ありがとうございました！
Ah, thanks for watching, thank you!
はーい！ ということで…
Hii! And so...
おっ、あー！ みん… あー！ いなくなった！
Oh, ah! Ever... ah! They're gone!
そういう牛って聞いてないですけど、なに？ みこも上がってきたよより、こんなね、できんだね
I didn't hear anything about cows like that, but we can do stuff like this, huh?
はーい！ ということて、それでは最後のVTRいきたいと思います！
Hii! And with that, we'll move on to the final VTR!
それでは、VTRどうぞー！
Now then, VTR, go ahead!
みこ先輩、本当に本当におめでとうございます！
Miko-senpai, huge, huge congratulations!
おかえりなさい！
Welcome back!
あなたもおうちに帰り！ありがとう！
Welcome back to you too! Thank you!
みこ先輩が帰ってきてくれると、もう本当に…
Having Miko-senpai come back, I really...
本当に嬉しい！
I'm truly so happy!
みこ先輩、うん、嬉しい。
Miko-senpai, yeah, I'm so happy.
いろいろね、一人で悩んだり、焦ったり、辛いこともあったと思いますがあ…
I'm sure you struggled alone, felt rushed, or had painful times, but...
うん、もう大丈夫。
Yeah, you're going to be fine.
これからのみこ先輩のまた楽しい配信が見れるのを楽しみにしています。
I'm looking forward to seeing Miko-senpai's fun streams again.
うん、また一緒に遊んでください！
Yeah, please play with me again!
ええ、もちろんこそ！おかえりなさい！
Of course! Welcome back!
みこ先輩！
Miko-senpai!
やっぱり、みこ先輩がいないと、ホロライブはホロライブじゃないというか、やっぱ何か欠けているような気がすると言うか、やっぱそういう現象が起きてしまうと思うんですよ、みこ先輩。
Without Miko-senpai, Hololive doesn't feel like Hololive—it feels like something is missing, Miko-senpai.
お帰りなさい！
Welcome back!
またみんなと一緒にたくさんいろんな配信遊んでください、誘ってください、おねがいします！一緒にARKもやりたいよ。
Please play streams and games together with everyone again, invite me! I want to play ARK together too.
また一緒に遊んでください！またどうぞお帰り！
Please play together again! Welcome back again!
みこ先輩！２周年と復帰、おめでとうございます！
Miko-senpai! Congratulations on your 2nd anniversary and your return!
すみません、あの、早速、角巻じゃんけんやっていいですか？
Can I start right away with a round of Tsunomaki Rock-Paper-Scissors?
いいよー！やった！
Sure! Yay!
角巻じゃんけん、角巻じゃんけん、角巻じゃんけん、角巻じゃんけん…
Tsunomaki Rock-Paper-Scissors, Tsunomaki Rock-Paper-Scissors...
じゃんけん、ぽん！
Rock, paper, scissors!
なん何のね… なん何のね、は… 個人指…
What's this... What's this finger...
これからいっぱいコラボとか、いっぱい遊んだりしましょうねー！
Let's do lots of collabs and play together from now on!
いいよー！いいよー！
Sure! Sure!
はやーい！ということでホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです。
Hii! This is Tokoyami Towa of Hololive 4th Generation.
みこ先輩、2周年と復帰おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます。
Miko-senpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary and return! Thank you so much.
元気になったみこ先輩が今日も見られて嬉しいです。うれしー。
I'm so happy to see a recovered Miko-senpai today. So happy.
まだまだ大変だとは思うんですけれど、落ち着いたら一緒にコラボしてゲームしてくれると嬉しいです。
I know things are still tough, but I'd be so happy if we could play games together once things settle down.
ではVTRまた新たにこれからよろしくお願いします。
Well then, looking forward to working with you anew from now on.
こちらこそ、よろしくお願いします、ありがとう！
Same here, looking forward to it, thank you!
おっ！んなあー！
Oh! Nnaa!
姫森！姫森ナイト、みこみこ先輩の活動2周年と復帰おめでとうなのら！なのらー！
Himemori Night, congratulations on Miko-senpai's 2nd anniversary and return, nanora!
また一緒に活動できて、本当に嬉しいなのら！
I'm truly so happy we can be active together again, nanora!
ルナはもっともっとみこみこ先輩と仲良くなりたいので、いつかコラボして遊んでくださいなのら！あそぼー！
Luna wants to get even closer, so please collab and play with me someday, nanora! Let's play!
おっはよー！おっはよー！
Good morning! Good morning!
みこみこ先輩にルーナが焼いたたい焼きのプレゼントを持ってきたので食べてください！
Mikomiko-senpai, Luna brought you taiyaki she baked as a present, so please eat up!
まじ？ありがとう。
Seriously? Thank you.
姫森ルーナなのだでしたー！
This was Himemori Luna!
ママも食べるんかぁい！
Are you eating it too?!
みこ先輩、にゃっはろー。
Miko-senpai, nyahalloh.
雪花ラミィです。みこ先輩、生き急ぎすぎです。
It's Yukihana Lamy. Miko-senpai, you're living way too fast.
みこ先輩、2周年、そして復帰3Dライブおめでとうございます。
Miko-senpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary and return 3D live.
みこ先輩はですね、ラミィがデビューしたときにまっさきに構ってくださった先輩です。
You were the first senior who looked after Lamy when she debuted.
そんな優しくてかわいくて赤ちゃんなみこ先輩と、これからもいろんなことを一緒にしてけたら嬉しいです。
I'm so happy to continue doing various things together with such a kind, cute, baby-like Miko-senpai.
それでは今後もいっそうのご活躍をお祈り申し上げます。
Wishing you even greater success moving forward.
ありがとう、ラミィでさー。
Thank you, this is Lamy.
ありがとうママ！ありがとう！
Thank you, Mama! Thank you!
みこ先輩！
Miko-senpai!
おかえりなさーい！おめでとう！
Welcome back! Congratulations!
みこ先輩の2周年、そしてご復帰おめでとうございまする！
Mikosenpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary and your return!
みこ先輩の声とお歌が大好きです！
I love Miko-senpai's voice and singing so much!
よければねねとも今度遊んでください！
If you'd like, please hang out with Nene sometime!
これからもよろしくお願いします！以上、桃鈴ねねでした！
Thank you for your continued support! That's all, Momosuzu Nene!
よろしくね、ねねちー！
Thanks, Nenechi!
みこ先輩、2周年＆復帰3Dライブおめでとうございます！
Miko-senpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary and return 3D live!
5期生が入ってきたとき、みこ先輩はまだお休みされていたときだったんですが、
When the 5th gen joined, Miko-senpai was still on hiatus,
復帰された今、これからたくさん一緒に関わることが出来ると思うので本当に嬉しいです。
but now that you're back, I'm really happy we'll be able to interact a lot from now on.
一緒にホロライブを盛り上げられるよう頑張りますので、みこ先輩と一緒に頑張っていきたいです。
I'll do my best to liven up Hololive together with Miko-senpai.
これからもよろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you!
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
みこ先輩ーー！
Miko-senpaiiii!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
尾丸ポルカと申します。えっと全然まだあの絡めてないのです。
My name is Omaru Polka. Um, we haven't really interacted much yet.
Twitterのした見たに、パニックパニック！
Seeing you on Twitter is like... panic panic!
これからも何卒よろしくお願いします。たくさんお話してコラボしてみたいです。
Looking forward to your continued support. I'd love to talk a lot and collab.
えっとですね、実わ、みこ先輩とお歌を歌いたいなって思ってるんです。なので、よければよろしくお願いいたします！
Actually, um, I've been thinking I'd love to sing a song with Miko-senpai. So if you're up for it, I'd appreciate it!
なんでも！なんでもポルカでしゅた！
Anything! This was Polka!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
生まれ立てのドキドキを響かせようよ
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time, with the best friends
キラメキの輪の中で
Inside the ring of radiance
覚えてるかな 最初の一歩
Do you remember? That very first step
私の小さな絵が 震えていたあの日
That day my small picture was trembling
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなと掴んだ空だよ
Is the sky we grasped together with everyone
もっともっともっともっともっと
More, more, more, more, more
加速するハートを
Accelerating our heartbeat
行くよ どこまでも
Let's go, no matter where
準備はオーケー？ 未来へ夢の扉を
Are you ready? Open the door to dreams toward the future
1・2・3 キラメキライダー☆
1, 2, 3, Kirameki Rider☆
生まれ立てのドキドキを響かせようよ
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time, with the best friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
You've been here, ever since you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ
I came here because I wanted to see you
みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
Let's sing together, an endless melody
キラメキの輪の中で
Inside the ring of radiance
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our newborn excitement resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best time and the best friends.
キラメキに乗って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
(イェーイ!)
(Yeah!)
覚えてるかな?最初の歌 (思い出深いね)
Do you remember? Our first song (So nostalgic, right?)
私 声が震えていた (ほんの少し)
My voice was trembling (Just a little bit)
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなで掴んだ今日だよ
Is today that we seized together.
もっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
More and more and more, our hearts accelerate!
(一緒に)行くよ どこまでも
(Together) Let's go anywhere,
(Are you ready?) 準備はok?
(Are you ready?) Are you ready?
ひらめけ!!夢のトビラを (123)
Open up!! The door of dreams (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our newborn excitement resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best time and the best friends.
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I came here wanting to see you, let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
届いているかな?私の声 (はっきりととは)
Is it reaching you? My voice (Not quite clearly)
届けたいのは君に笑顔 (そのスマイル!)
What I want to convey is your smile (That smile!)
理想の遠さに悔しくて
Frustrated by how far my ideals were,
みんなで泣き笑ったね
we cried and laughed together.
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 全て抱きしめ
Hold tight, hold tight, hold tight, hold everything close!
(一緒に)行こう どこまでも
(Together) Let's go anywhere,
(Are you ready?) 準備はok?
(Are you ready?) Are you ready?
すすめ!!希望の道を (123)
Press forward!! The path of hope (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play my favorite feelings colorfully,
最高の場所 最高のみんなと
in the best place with the best everyone.
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm right here, it's no illusion—
君の心が幸せに染まるように
so that your heart is dyed with happiness.
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って☆
Layering our harmonies, draped in sparkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing,
そんな願いわがままも いいでしょ?
is such a selfish wish alright?
だって楽しくて もうとまらない!!
Because it's too much fun and I can't stop!!
輝くステージで もっともっと!!(お願い)ずっと!!
On this shining stage, more and more!! (Please) forever!!
(オー!) (イェーイ!)
(Oh!) (Yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Words like happy, fun, or beloved aren't enough
今も 今も 悩みはあるけど
even though right now, I still have worries.
ここにいるよ 私 ここにいるよ
I'm right here, I am right here,
君と同じ 世界を見つめて
gazing at the same world as you.
(行くよ!) (キラメキライダー☆)
(Let's go!) (Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our newborn excitement resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best time and the best friends.
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう(せーのっ!)
I came here wanting to see you, let's sing together (Ready, set!)
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
見つけてくれたから
Because you found me,
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう せーのっ!
I came here wanting to see you, let's sing together, ready set!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
終わらないメロディ
An endless melody,
キラメキ君のワケ
The reason for the sparkle in you,
キラメキ纏って☆
Draped in sparkle☆
(イェーイ!)
(Yeah!)
はい！というわけでキラメキライダーを歌わせていただきました！
Yes! So, we just sang Kirameki Rider!
ありがとうございます！あー、なんかね、ソロライブの曲っていいよね。
Thank you so much! Ah, you know, songs from solo lives are really nice.
神だね。
They're divine.
なんかいろいろ重なる、ね？
Various things overlap, you know?
はい、ということで、ここまでね、メドレーのほうを重ねてのライブをさせていただいたんですけども、
Yes, so up to now, we've had this medley-style live performance, but...
なんと、もう残すところあと1曲早いね！
amazingly, there's only one song left! That was fast!
なんか絶対無理だなって思ったけど、意外と気持ちが乗って、動けたよ！
I thought it'd be totally impossible, but somehow my feelings got into it and I was able to move!
いつもこのポーズだけど、もっとね、みこもアイドルっぽくパフォーマンスがもっとできるように頑張ります！
I always do this pose, but I'll do my best so Miko can perform even more like an idol!
そのための休養だったから、もっといろんな舞台で、みこも1年前のこれだけじゃなくて、もっといい
That's what the break was for, so on various stages, not just this from a year ago, but even better
パフォーマンスができるように頑張ります！エリートアイドル、ありがと！
so I can give an even better performance, I'll do my best, elite idol! Thanks!
はい、ということで、残すところあと1曲なんですけれども、みこからお知らせがあります！イェーイ！
Yes, so there's only one song left, but I have an announcement from Miko! Yay!
それではまず1つめ、1つめいきます！2つめの告知は…あ、みんなもうさしている、あ、こっちだった！
So first, let's go with the first one! The second announcement... ah, everyone already knows it, ah, it's this!
あ、売れやー！はい、ということで、あ、実これね、あの2周年の時にも出そうかなと思ったりとかしてたんですけど、ちょっと時期が遅れてね、出になりましたのが、さくらみこ復活記念ボイス発売となります！
Ah, it's out! Yes, actually, I was thinking of releasing this around the 2nd anniversary, but the timing got delayed, and what's being released is the Sakura Miko Return Commemoration Voice!
豪華なんです。
It's luxurious!
何が豪華かというとですね、
What makes it so luxurious, you ask?
えーっと、豪華と言うと、
Well, when I say luxurious...
いや、まずね、あの絵がエッチだと。
First of all, the illustration is... quite ecchi!
あのね、これね、全体出したいと思ったんだけどね、上司がね、これをもっとパンチ、エッチすぎてダメですって
You know, I wanted to show the whole thing, but my boss said it was too ecchi and wouldn't allow it!
言われたんで、あれなんですけど、なんか、ミコがね、とってもしゃ、
So that's how it is, but you know... Miko is, like, very...
あの、すっごい好きなエッチさんなんですよ、実はね。
She really loves ecchi stuff, actually!
桂先生、桂先生がね、描いていただいたんですよ。
Katsura-sensei, Katsura-sensei drew this for us.
いや、本当にめちゃくちゃこの質感、
Seriously, this texture,
足、そして脇、そして手のひらまで！
the legs, the armpits, and even the palms!
凝ってますね、これは！すごい描き込みです！
It's so detailed, this is amazing artwork!
で、こちらがですね、えっと、ポストカードと、そしてアクリルパネルに
And here, we have the postcard and the acrylic panel.
なります。アクリルパネル、こっちがこっちなですね。
Yes, the acrylic panel, that's this one here.
あ、ちょっともう一回戻ってもいいですか。ごめんなさい。
Ah, can we go back for a moment? Sorry!
それでですね、あのね、何がね、もう一つ豪華かというと、もちろん、あのイラストもすごいんだけど、
So, you know, what else makes it luxurious? Of course, the illustration is amazing, but...
ミコが、もう、あの、好きな、ピ、あ、エロゲ、おっと、スナイ。
Miko, well... her favorite, pi— ah, eroge— oops, no. Eroge, you ask?
エロゲ、あ、なんですか?って言われた時に、ミコが一番、あの初めにやって、最後までやって、
When people ask, "What kind of eroge?", Miko started with this one, played it all the way to the end,
すっごいはまったクローバーデイズっていうね、エロゲが、あ、ごめんなさいね。
and got totally hooked on it—it's called Clover Days! Ah, sorry about that.
エロゲがあるんですけど、あ、ミコはエロゲ好きなんですけど、知らない人いるかもしれないんですけど、
There's this eroge... I love eroge, though some of you might not know it.
あの、ミコはめちゃくちゃ美少女ゲーム好きなんですけど、で、あの、あるかこさんのクローバーデイズっていうね、
Miko loves bishoujo games so much, and there's this wonderful eroge called Clover Days by Alcot-san,
素晴らしいエロゲがあるんですけど、え、そちらのシナリオをね、あの、書かれている、空下先生に、なんと！ミコボイスドラマの台本書いてもらったんだよー！やったー！ありがとうございます！
and Soshita-sensei, who wrote the scenario for it, actually wrote the script for Miko's voice drama! Yay! Thank you so much!
本当に嬉しい！本当に嬉しい！
I'm so happy! I'm truly so happy!
アイラブユー、アイラブユー、アイラブユー、声優エロゲ、おい！
I love you, I love you, I love you, voice actor eroge, hey!
で、え、そのね、題名がミコと夏休み、ミコと夏休みです。
And, the title is "Miko and Summer Vacation," "Miko and Summer Vacation."
で、こちらのボイスドラマになってるんですけど、あの、めちゃくちゃね、SEとかBGMとかプロの方にやっていただいたので、とってもね、凝ってます！セリフの音とか全て。なので聞いてほしいです。
And it's a voice drama, and since it was made by professionals for the SE and BGM, it's extremely polished! Everything from the sound effects to the voice lines. So I really want you to listen to it.
ということでグッズ紹介、パン！
And with that, goods introduction—bam!
そう、あのね、本当にすごいの。
That's right, you know, it really is amazing.
そして、なんと、気になった方もいるだろう、さっき見えて、なんと、おっぱいマウスパッド作っちゃったんだよな、これ。
And what's more, for those who were wondering—as you saw earlier—I actually made an oppai mousepad!
まさかさ、ミコさ、あの、こんなに長期でね、お休みするってね、その当時2周年を準備してて思ってなかったんで、
I never expected that Miko would take such a long break back when I was preparing for the 2nd anniversary.
こんなにエモい、あの、感じになると思ってなかったので、ちょっと、あの、雰囲気をね、こう、壊しちゃうかもしれないんだけど、
I didn't think it would turn out so emotional, so maybe this breaks the mood a bit, but...
ミコ、おっぱいマウスパッド作ってもらったー！
Miko got an oppai mousepad made for her!
これね、これ、やばいね、これ。
This is—this is crazy, right?
ということで、え、こちらね、先生に描いていただいたおっぱいマウスパッドも、え、このグッズの中にね、入っております。
So, yes, the oppai mousepad drawn by the teacher is also included inside these goods.
そして、え、夏休みのね、ひたすらね、休日に書いてたミコ日記をまとめたミコ日記本、そしてTwitter未公開ページありなのでね、ぜひ、あの、楽しんでくれたらなと思います。
And, the Miko Diary book compiling all the Miko Diaries I wrote endlessly during summer vacation, plus unpublished Twitter pages, so I really hope you enjoy it!
そして、その絵日記の中でも、あの、どんどん、火力がね、休んでるうちに上がっていったと言われる、こちらの、えっと、こうひょ、だった、え、絵日記の中から、あ、おこ、起こして、ミコが起こして、絵本にしたので、こちらも、ぜひね、4周年入っているので、あ、ぜひじゃらじゃらとつけてください。
And within that picture diary, from the picture diary that people say got increasingly high-fire/skilled while I was resting, I turned it into a picture book, so please attach it jingly-jangling since it's part of the 4th anniversary!
はい、という感じです。こちらが以上グッズ紹介。
Yep, that's about it. That concludes the goods introduction.
あ、もう一、もうあると。そう！
Ah, wait, there's one more? That's right!
あの、先着がね、あるって言ったじゃないですか。
You know how I said there was a first-come bonus?
そう、先着がね、先着のものがあるんですよ。
Yes, there are first-come-first-served items.
それが、あの、こちらのポストカード。ポストカード、これからね、販売開始されるであろう、あれなんですけど、ポストカードが、
That is, this postcard. The postcard that will start selling soon—wait, the postcard...
あの、ミコのおしゃれメッセージ付き、あ、こちらですね。こちらがね、数量限定となっておりますが、
has Miko's original handwritten message attached! Ah, this one here. This is available in limited quantities, but...
ミコはね、お願いして、増やしてもらったんです！
Miko begged them and had them make more!
絶対頑張って運んで！つって、あの、増やしてもらったので、
Saying, "Please work hard and deliver them!" so they increased the quantity.
なので、こちらはぜひね、あの、ゲットしてみてください。
So please try and get your hands on this one.
あの、先着じゃなくても、あの、手に入るのでね、サインの複製品のやつは、ありますので。
Even if you miss out on the first-come bonus, you can still get the one with the replica signature.
ただ、あの、メッセージの手書きがちょっと、少なめげと。いうことです。
It's just that the handwritten message part is a bit more limited. That's all.
詳しくは概要欄っていうか、ブースまでよろしくお願いします。そして、
For details, please check the description box—or rather, the Booth page! And...
次のお知らせ！これね、大変お待たせしてま、お待たせしてしまったんですけれども、
Next announcement! I'm so sorry to have kept you waiting, but...
こちらです！
here it is!
なんと、「さくらかぜ」
Ta-da! "Sakurakaze"!
みこのええセカンドオリジナルソングの「さくらかぜ」が10月22日零時より
Miko's... um, second original song, "Sakurakaze,"
えっと、このあと、もうすぐだね、あと20時間ぐらいから、iTunes、え、などのね、音楽配信サービスで、え、順次配信決定いたしました！
will be released starting at midnight on October 22nd on iTunes, Spotify, Apple Music, and other music distribution services!
ありがとうございます！おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations, congratulations, congratulations!
こちらね、ぜひね、あの、ゲット、してくれたらな、ダウンロードしてくれたらなって、思います。
Everyone, please be sure to go and download it,
なんか、あの、アラームとかにね、設定もできますし、ぜひね、あの、お、お願いします！
you can also set it on your alarms and stuff, so please, I really, really ask you to!
あ、運営さんも、あの、ありがとうございます！
Ah, and to management as well, thank you very much!
はい。という感じでございます。
Yes! So that's how it is.
ありがとう！嬉しいよね、みこちっちゃ。
Thank you! I'm so happy, right, Miko-chachi?
あ、カラオケ配信もね、もしかしたらお進んでいるかもしれないです。
Ah, karaoke streaming might also be coming soon, maybe?
はい。
Yes.
というこで、あれ？
So, um...
あれ？画面が戻らない。
Wait, the screen won't return.
たーーん！
Transition!
お、できたできたできた。
Ah, it came, it came, it came!
はい。
Yes.
ということで、え、あ、はい。
So, um...
えっと、今ね、あの言われたんですけど、
Um, right now, as I was just told...
なんと！このあと21日から22、あ、間違えた。
Not only that, starting on the 22nd...
22日からですね、みこの配信のあとに、ねんどろいどさんの新商品もありますので、
From the 22nd, after Miko's stream, there's going to be a new Miko merchandise release!
みなさん、手に入れてください！きっと、おみこが、お、ドキドキしちゃうような新商品なんだろうな。
So everyone, please go get it! I'm sure Miko's...
ね？というわけでぜひね、配信のあともよろしくお願いします。
Right? So please look forward to the stream afterwards as well!
はい。
Yes.
というこで、え、残りも、あとわずかになりました。
And so, um... there's just a little bit left.
あ、もう、少々待ってね、ごめんね。あの、このあとは、みこのお話をちょっとだけさせていただげたらなって、思います。
Ah, wait a second, sorry. Um, after this, I want to talk a little bit about Miko...
えっと、Twitterにはね、お手紙を投稿したんですけど、あの、Twitterにはお手紙を投稿して、なんか書いてたんですけど、今日のめために、この時間のために、なんかあんまりまとまらなくて、
Um, I posted a letter on Twitter, but... um, I wrote a letter on Twitter...
よし。えー、みなさん、みなさんに、
Yosh. Um... everyone...
みこが、この休養期間ね、たくさん支えられて、
Miko... during this suspension period, you supported Miko so much,
本当に、たくさん待ってくれて、ありがとう！本当に、
and really waited for her so much, thank you so much.
とりあえず、自分初めは、ただいまっと「ありがとう」って伝えたかったんだよね。うん。
First of all, I wanted to say "thank you" as soon as I returned.
いや、あの、3か月間、休養をね、決めるって時、
Yeah, um, for those three months of suspension...
すごく、すごくね、みこ、嫌で。
deciding to take a break, I was really... really, you know, Miko was scared.
みんなとさ、毎日配信してて、VTuberの、うーん、1週間なんて1か月みたいなもんで、時間が本当に1つ1つ1日1日大切で、そんなね、そんな、活動をしているのに、
Everyone and I streamed every day, and VTubers' weeks are like a month, so time is really precious, day by day.
みこ、3か月とか、ま、その時は、あの、どのくらいの休みになるか正直あんまり分かってなくて、
Miko... for three months, or at that time, I honestly didn't really understand how long of a break it would be,
んで、それでお休みをしたほうがいいって言われた時に、すごく不安だったんですね。
and so, when I was told "you should take a break," I got really anxious.
みんなに、忘れられてしまうのかな、とか、
Would everyone... forget about me, or something?
みこ、みんなが進んでるのに、止まらないで、走り続けてるのに、みこだけ止まってしまって、
Miko... everyone was moving forward, but I wouldn't stop, and keep running,
それで、すごい不安でした。でも、
and that made me really anxious. But...
みんなこうやって、ずっと待ってくれて、あの時不安だったみこに、今、このこの瞬間を見せてあげたいなって、思う、
everyone stayed and waited for me like this, and I want to show that anxious Miko this wonderful moment right now,
そのぐらい決めるまでのやっってて、
is what I kept thinking until I decided.
それで、2周年のね、8月1日の2周年の1日前に、休止活動休止することを知らせてもらって、
And then, just one day before the 2nd anniversary—August 1st—I was notified of the resumption of activities.
なんか、本当に必死につかなかったんだけど、休んでる間も、みんながたくさん待ってるよって言ってくれて、元気な姿で会いたいって言ってくれて、スタッフさんも、
I was really nervous the whole time, but during the break, everyone kept saying "We're waiting for you," and "We want to see your energetic self, let's meet," and the staff too...
こういう、大切なな、いつか、ね、ときに、もしものことがあったら
always... at important times like this, if there's ever something I miss...
ったら、ステージに立てなくなったら、
If I couldn't stand on stage anymore,
さくらみこさんがそこに立てなかったら嫌にしていつも言ってくれて
and Sakura Miko told me she'd hate it if she couldn't stand there, always telling me...
すごく決心がついて今こうやって立ってます。
it really helped me make up my mind, and now I'm standing here.
本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much.
準備中にこのライブのみんなもたくさんDMとかね、リプとかね、
During preparations, everyone for this live sent me so many DMs and replies...
たくさんしてくれて本当に勇気とか支えられたというか
and really gave me courage and supported me...
なんて言っていいのかわかんないね。
I don't even know what to say.
なので本当に本当に、本当に本当に、みんなに「ありがとう」って思います。
So really, truly, from the bottom of my heart, thank you everyone.
そしてみこはね、今日からまた、これからはもっともっと、前よりももっとエリートに、アイドルになっていくために、
And Miko, starting today and moving forward... to become an even more elite idol than before,
みんなをたくさん元気もらった分、元気をお返しできるように、
to be able to return all the energy you've given me,
みこ、たくさんたくさん、これからも頑張ります！
Miko will keep doing her absolute best!
だから、これからもみこのことを応援してくれますか？
So, will you keep supporting Miko from now on?
本当に素敵なファンのみなさんに恵まれて本当に幸せです。本当に本当に、ありがとう！
I am so blessed to have such wonderful fans. Thank you so, so much!
ということでね、そんな気持ちも込めて、最後の曲歌いたいと思います。
With all those feelings, I'd like to sing my final song.
最後の曲はみこのセカンドオリジナルソングの「サクラカゼ」です！聴いてください。
The last song is my second original song, "Sakurakaze"! Please listen.
箱にあたる陽を横目で眺めて
Gazing sideways at the sunlight hitting the box,
そっと陰る木の根に一人で比べてた
I compared myself alone to the softly shadowed tree roots.
積もる溜息を吹き払うように
As if blowing away my piling sighs,
そんなそれを君が見つけてくれたんだ
you were the one who found me.
そう それは恋のようなぬくもりを
Yes, it was like the warmth of love,
君に笑顔咲かせたら
making a smile bloom on your face.
桜風に踊る空君と出会えたこの場所で
In this place where I met you, dancing in the cherry blossom wind,
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっと溢れそうになるかな
I wonder how many memories are about to overflow.
君と流した涙は明日の笑顔の糧にしよう
Let's turn the tears we shed together into nourishment for tomorrow's smiles.
膝をついてたってほら何回だっていいよ
Even if we dropped to our knees, hey, any number of times is fine.
意地を張って 恥をかいて
Putting on airs, feeling embarrassed,
君が傍で見守ってくれたこと
knowing you watched over me by my side—
わかってるから
because I know that.
追い風を受けてとまらない日々も
Even days when I caught the tailwind and couldn't stop,
そっと挫けそうになって心が疼いた
quietly feeling like I might break, my heart aching.
積もる溜息でまた泣きかけても
Even when I almost cried again with my piling sighs,
あたたかな手でずっと支えてくれたんだ
you always supported me with your warm hands.
ほら 耳を澄ませば 一人じゃないから
See, if you listen closely, you're not alone.
諦めかけて心が閉じても
Even when I gave up and my heart closed,
君が背中を押してくれたよね
you pushed me forward, didn't you?
春の蕾が花開く頃は隣で笑い合おうね
When spring buds bloom into flowers, let's laugh together side by side.
桜風に踊る空君と出会えたこの場所で
In this place where I met you, dancing in the cherry blossom wind,
桜風に踊る空 君と出会ったこの場所で
Dancing in the cherry blossom breeze, in this sky where I met you,
どれくらいの思い出ギュッと溢れそうになるかな
how many memories are about to overflow?
君と描くこの花は 未来もきっと残るから
This flower we sketched together will surely remain in our future.
意地を張って 恥をかいて
Act stubborn, feel embarrassed,
いじけだって それでも 君が傍で見守ってくれたんだ
even when teased, I grow stronger because you were there by my side watching over me.
ありがとうだよ！
Thank you so much!
君と出会ええたこの空 これからもっと咲かせるよ
Dancing in the cherry blossom breeze, in this sky where I met you,
ありがとうごさいました！
Thank you so much!
また次の放送でお会いしましょう！おつみか！
Let's meet again on the next broadcast! Mitsumika!
君からのひとことを 僕らずっと持っているから
With the word you gave me, which I've held onto all this time,
急かすつもりはないさ 歩きやすいペースでいい
there's no need to rush, a comfortable pace is fine.
当たり前だった日々が 特別だったんだって
Days that used to be ordinary felt so special,
優しく吹いた《サクラカゼ》が 気付かせてくれたんだ
the gently blowing cherry blossom breeze made me realize that.
ねえ 味気ない毎日に笑顔をくれる君に
To you who brings a smile to my dreary days,
届けたいこのメロディ 繋いでいくから
I want to deliver this melody and keep passing it on.
「おかえり！」僕らが紡ぐ 伝えたいひとこと。
"Welcome home!" That's the one thing we want to convey,
ずっといつまでも待っているからね僕ら
and we'll wait forever and ever, so me and you...
この先何年の未来はまだ分からないけど 笑い合える日が続けばいいな
This future years ahead is still unknown, but I hope days of laughing together continue.
なにより大切なものは
More than anything else,
「ただいま！」それだけ ただそれだけ そのひとこと。を持っているんだ
"I'm home!", just that, just that alone, holding onto that one word.